# SUHAIB MUTAWAKEL

# SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN UX/UI DESIGNER

#### **ABOUT ME**

I have a great passion for **Software Development** and UI/UX design. I spent the past two years working and learning about the field of Autonomous Driving. Alongside that, I enjoy creating beautiful User Interfaces, iOS Apps and providing customers with great **User Experience**. I have won some awards from my UI designs. I love working as part of a team in which I can grow and be able to contribute to building softwares that can change our future.

#### PROJECTS/AWARDS

- Reconnect Conference (iOS App) Published in the App Store https://apps.apple.com/app/id1480120486 - Oct 2019
- ScheduleFy (iOS App) Mhacks Hackathon Third Place Winner - Oct 2019
- FlagSter (iOS App) GrizzHacks 4 Hackathon Third Place Winner - Sep 2019 Best Mobile App Winner - Sep 2019
- Meal Delivery UI Design (Charming UI Designer Award)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Java Programming
- Swift
- C Programming
- Python
- Coding / CSS
- Wordpress / CMS

#### **SOFTWARE**

- Photoshop
- After Effects
- Adobe XD
- Premiere
- Illustrator
- TPT, DOORS, MKS
- Intellii
- Eclipse

#### **HONORS & LEADERSHIP**

- Distinguished Officer Team PTK May 2017
- Outstanding Student Leader Award HFC April 2017.
- Honors Program Graduate- HFC May 2017
- Phi Theta Kappa Scholarship Recipient-April 2017.
- Council for World Scholarship Recipient- April 2016.







suhaibmutawakel.com



suhaibtarea@amail.com



github.com/suhaiboon

in linkedin.com/in/suhaibmutawakel

#### **EDUCATION**

2017 / 2019 EASTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY - Ypsilanti, MI BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE - (Expected Dec 2019)

2015 / 2017

HENRY FORD COLLEGE - DEARBORN, MI

**ASSOCIATE IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEM** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

JAN.2018 - CURRENT

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Bosch USA, Plymouth, MI

- Perform software development and requirements engineering according to the V-model.
- Worked on redesigning the APA system through MATLAB with 5 other teammates.
- Create design documentation in both text and model-based formats.
- Perform reviews for requirements, designs, and implementations.
- Used TPT to generate full coverage testing reports for models and software implementation.

#### SEP.2017 - CURRENT

#### **FOUNDER**

Qumri Design LLC, Dearborn, MI | Our work: suhaibmutawakel.com

- · Worked as part of a team of three to deliver great high-quality Websites and Apps.
- Worked closely with the team to design beautiful UI Designs and Prototypes.
- Built Apps that are customizable and user-friendly.
- Designed all types of flyer, posters, and advertisements.

#### AUG.2017 - DEC 2017

#### WEB SUPPORT CO-OP

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- · Maintained content on HFC websites using the Drupal content management framework
- Created or extend Drupal websites as needed by maintaining content types and views.
- Developed and maintain documentation for end users.
- Provided technical support for content editor and owners as needed.

### JAN.2016 - MAY 2017

## LEADERSHIP AND STUDENTS MENTORSHIP

Henry Ford College, Dearborn, MI

- Educated new students about various resources and student services available at HFC
- Visited classes and gave informational talks and sessions to first year students.
- · Coordinated and facilitate social and educational programs as desired or needed.
- Met individually with the Dean of Students to discuss new student concerns, as needed.